I warned you not to go out tonight!
Maniac is a horror film directed by William Lustig.
A psychotic man, troubled by his childhood abuse, kills and mutilates
young women and local models on the streets of New York City.
Frank Zito, played by Joe Spinell.
Anna D'Antoni, played by Caroline Munro.
Rita, played by Abigail Clayton.
Carmen Zito, played by Nelia Bacmeister.
Denise, played by Denise Spagnuolo.
Billy, played by Billy Spagnuolo.
Maniac is a 1980 American psychological slasher film
directed by William Lustig and written by C.
Rosenberg and Joe Spinell.
It stars Spinell as Frank Zito, an Italian-American serial killer
residing in New York City who murders and scalps young women.
With a minuscule budget, many scenes in the film were shot guerrilla style.
Originally considered an exploitation film, Maniac has since attained
a cult following despite receiving polarized reviews.
The film was remade in 2012 by director Franck Khalfoun and produced by
Alexandre Aja, starring Elijah Wood in the lead role.
While not prosecuted for obscenity nor officially listed as a video nasty, Maniac was seized by various police forces across Greater
Manchester and Lancashire during the video nasty panic, presumably based on the film's notorious reputation overseas.
The film explores themes of mannequin, sadism,
shotgun, murder of prostitute, gore.
The tone is dark.